arithmetic mean 平均
circumference of a circle	周长
perimeter of a square		周长
diameter of a circle	直径
equilateral triangle	等边
tangent to	相切
quadrilateral	四边形， square正方形， rectangle矩形
mode of a list	众数
right triangle	直角三角形
isosceles	等腰
hypotenuse	斜边
The first quartile number   1/4的位置（中位数是1/2的位置），third quatile, 90 percentile
interquatile range	从1/4到3/4的距离
revenue per student	收入/学生数
enrollment		入学人数
grant		资助
revenue		只是收入，并不是净利润！net revenue才是
wholesale	批发	retail
first quadrant	第一象限
units digit	个位数
The ratio of w to y	w/y
on the circle, in the circle
as a percent	写%之前的就行，		as a decimal
positive number！ 不要看成positive integer
quotient 商	remainder

1.414^2 = 2   1.732^2 = 3   2.236^2 = 5


1. must be filled to at least 50% of its total capacity without overflowing
	without overflowing!!!!

2. N equals the number of positive 3-digit numbers that contain odd digits only
	N == 125

3. charts shown may contain a lot of inane things
	and you may have to estimate the value from the chart given

4. Probability of getting exactly 2 heads when A coin is flipped 5 times
	C(5,3) * 0.5^3 * 0.5^2

5. the account compounds quarterly
	每个季度发一下利息

6. Sid intended to type a seven-digit number, but the two 3's he meant to type did not appear. What appeared instead was the five-digit number 52115. How many different seven-digit numbers could Sid have meant to type?
	C(7,2)   (choose from 7 blanks)

7. Average (arithmetic mean) of integers from -50 to -1 inclusive.
Average (arithmetic mean) of integers from -50 to 0 inclusive.
	the second one is greater

8. pass below point A
	means not through it

9. 60% concentrated solution
	60% 浓度的溶液

10. In how many different ways can 3 boys and 3 girls be seated in a row of 6 chairs such that the girls are not separated, and the boys are not separated?
	A(3,3)*A(3,3)*2
	three boys can have different permutation

11. 85% of the men choose ...
	85/100 = 17/20
	so the total number of men must be divisible by 20

12. (1/2)^-4 == 2^4

13. a prime number is greater than 1 !!!

14. when counting divisors,
	remember to count 1 !!!

15. 带进去算！！

16. number of diagonals of a ten sided poligon
	C(10,2) - 10

17. 0.05 percent of x
	means 0.05%

18. If profits increase 20% from 2006 to 2007
	注意你是知道2006还是2007的！

19. 等圆的等长弦所对圆周角相等

20. n is a positive integer, and k is the product of all integers from 1 to n inclusive. If k is a multiple of 1440, then the smallest possible value of n is
	1440 除以1,2,3,4，。。。 

21. In a group of 45 children, 60 percent of the children are boys, and 60 percent of the children are left-handed.
	so at least 45*0.6 + 45*0.6 -45 = 9 children are left-handed boys

22. (-1/2)^N > -8
	note that N can be any even number, both positive and negative

23. 16,000 has how many positive divisors?
	16000 = 2^7 * 5^3
	so its divisor is of the form 2^N * 5^M, where N can be 0-7, M can be 0-3
	so 8*4=32
	(note that 1 is already included, in the case of N=M=0)

24. we have r^2 = x^2 +36, 5r = 5x + 9, what is x+r
	(r-x)(r+x) = 36, 5(r-x) = 9

25. 有多个坐标的图表要很小心！不要看错个！！

26. P(A and B) = P(A) + P(B) - P(A or B)	甘特图！！

27. A box contains 10 balls numbered from 1 to 10 inclusive. If Ann removes a ball at random and replaces it, and then Jane removes a ball at random, what is the probability that both women removed the same ball?
	1/10

28. driving from A to B with an average speed of 40, and from B to A with 60,
	compare the total average speed with 50
	not equal!!

29. A librarian has three identical copies of a single cookbook and four different novels that he wants to display. Assuming all seven books will be in a single row, how many different arrangements can he make?
	A(7,7) / A(3,3)

21. Set A: {1, 3, 4, 6, 9, 12, 15}
If three numbers are randomly selected from set A without replacement, what is the probability that the sum of the three numbers is divisible by 3?
	C(5,3) / C(7,3)

22. What is the sum of each distinct prime factor of 9999?
	distinct！！！

23. Which BMI groups have representatives on this graph with BMR > 1600 kcal/day?
	representative意思是有代表的数据，一个就算有

24. 4x4的表格，其中填满x，y，z，w，已知四行各自的和，其中三列的和，求另外一列的和
	把四行加起来减掉三列就行

25. Which of the following could be the number of zeroes, to the left of the decimal point, contained in n?
	小数点左边的0，没说是连续的！！

26. (x+y)(x-y)<8, x+y>3, 0<y<x  what is the greatest possible value of x?
	x+y>=4, x-y>0, so x-y == 1 !!
	然后一个一个去试

27. 估算0.83333
	= 0.8 + 0.03333 = 4/5 + 1/30 = 5/6

28. Two sides of triangle DEF are equal to 3. Which of the following, taken alone, would be sufficient in finding the area of triangle DEF?
	The ratio of DE to EF = 1 : √2			no！DE和EF都可能是腰
	The sum of angles DEF and EFD is 135 degrees	no！
	The sum of angles DEF and FDE is 90 degrees	yes！

29. the sum of 1-9 is 45!!! 

30. If a, b, c and d are different integers between -6 and 10 inclusive, what is the least possible value of the product abcd?
	10 * 9 * 8 * -6

31. 让你比较两组数的标准差，可能是让你观察一下两组数的特征就行

32. If 8^(n+1) + 8^n = 36, then n =?
	(8+1) * 8^n = 36
	8^n = 4

33. w=x^2*y+x+3y, 判断w、x、y奇偶关系
	干脆列个x、y的枚举表，也就四行

34. In basketball, when Monica takes her first free throw, she has a 50% chance of scoring. If she takes an additional throw, she has a 75% chance of scoring on this throw if she scored on the immediately previous throw, but only a 25% chance of scoring on this throw if she didn't score on the immediately previous throw. Suppose she has to take a set of three free throws in a row, and she doesn't score on the first one. What is the probability that she scores at least once on one of the subsequent two throws?
	1 - (3/4)*(3/4)	
	（记得用1去减！）
	
35. if x > 21/40, x can be ? 11/20? 13/25? 31/60?
	并不是糖水问题，因为不是1/2上下同时加1，
	化成1/2 + ？ 来比较

36. How many three-digit numbers are there such that all three digits are different and the first digit is not zero?
	9 * 9 * 8

37. In a population of chickens, the average (arithmetic mean) weight is 6.3 pounds, and the standard deviation is 1.2 pounds. Which of the following weights (in pounds) are within 1.5 units of standard deviation of the mean?
	1.5 units of standard deviation = standard deviation * 1.5

38. What was the percent decrease in the number of Japanese graduates from 2003 to 2004?
	意思是数量减少的比例

39. Tuk weighs 60 percent more than Kim, Lee weighs 50 percent less than Tuk, and Pat weighs 25 percent more than Lee. If Pat weighs 126 pounds, what is Kim’s weight?
	T = 1.6 K
	L = 0.5 T
	P = 1.25 L
	so, P = 1.25 * 0.5 * 1.6 T = T

40. 没说平行就不是平行，图里都是骗人的

41. A weighted die, numbered one through six, has a probability of 1/4 of rolling a six. If this die is rolled three times, and each roll is independent, what is the probability of rolling at least two sixes?
	P = P(three sixes) + P(exactly two sixes) = 1/4 * 1/4 * 1/4 + 1/4 * 1/4 * 3/4  记得乘3/4！！！
	
